Wie ist es der Gemeinschaft des Kibbutz gelungen, wieder Halt zu finden?
we know this very well already,
because it’s not our first attack unfortunately...
Something really miraculous happens in those situations.
The people we live next to...
have long stopped being our friends and neighbors,
they are, we are brothers in arms.
We've been through so much together,
I remember,
just in the middle of the night,
sometimes...
people around the world don’t even know about it,
but we have what we call,
we call it
"drizzles"
of rockets...
I can be here in my house and suddenly out of the blue,
there's an attack of rockets coming in and...
sometimes it starts a conflict,
so...
You need to get up in the middle of the night,
pack your children with everything,
find a safe window
when it’s fairly quiet,
and you just get out of the kibbutz.
Now...
there were so many situations in which I found myself,
3am walking with my...
my daughter in my car,
my husband always had to stay here,
because he's manager of...
managing animals,
so you can’t just leave the animals and go,
So, it was always me and my kids,
I remember situations,
crazy situations like 3am,
I'm driving out of the kibbutz with my daughter,
she's...
2 years old and I'm pregnant with my other child,
and I'm driving out of the kibbutz,
and there are rockets.
Rockets passing me and...
Iron Dome, all over my head and I drive and then,
I get a phone call
from a friend from the kibbutz saying,
"I found a place to stay this night".
"I'm saving you a room, waiting for you",
the location...
and I get there and I have everything waiting for me.
This community is unbelievable.
Living here,
when people speak to me,
used to speak to me, all the time about security,
"Do you know your neighbors where you live?",
because I know that I have neighbors,
that will take care of me,
and my children...
just the same as they will take care of them,
and their children. And this is what we have here,
I remember myself during alarms many times,
with my children...
and, other...
children of the kibbutz,
I remember grabbing my child on one hand,
and another child...
one of my neighbors' in another hand running to shelter,
and I think that knowing...
I think that this community lives according to values,
that in many parts of the world are long,
long forgotten...
And this is one of the reasons why it was so hard,
and it is still so hard,
to find a new place or to think about living,
or to think about...
this is a very strong situation.
Now we also understand there could be, after
such a trauma, we could be in a...
a kibbutz assembly...
Sit all together and try to figure out
what to do,
and then somebody will start shouting or do something,
and people understand that it comes from the trauma.
There's a...
certain way of accepting and understanding,
where people are at...
So this community is really unbelievable,
in those things...